Guide to the Trautwine family papers, 1834-1947.
Trautwine family papers, 1834-1947.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Trautwine family papers, 1834-1947.
760
Trautwine family.
7.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, clippings, photographs, and other material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, diaries, clippings, photographs, and other material relating largely to the engineering interests of John Cresson Trautwine, Sr., II, and III.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, diaries, clippings, photographs, and other material relating largely to the engineering interests of John Cresson Trautwine, Sr. (1810-83), II (1850-1924), and III (1878-1949). Papers concern railroad promotion and construction (1844-49); experiences of Trautwine, Sr., while he worked in New Granada, and conditions in that province (1844-49); engineering matters; student letters; papers relating to Samuel Ashbridge, former mayor of Philadelphia (1906), the 1912 presidential campaign, the League to Enforce Peace (1916-18), and a letter (1887) from Oliver Wendell Holmes to Mrs. Trautwine. Correspondents include William H. Balch, Clinton Lathrop Bogert, John Ripley Freeman, the American Society of Civil Engineers, and the Philadelphia Bureau of Water.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Trautwine family.; Ashbridge, Samuel.; Balch, William H.; Bogert, Clinton Lathrop.; Freeman, John Ripley.; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894.; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1810-1883.; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1850-1924.; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1878-1949.; American Society of Civil Engineers.; League to Enforce Peace (U.S.); Philadelphia Bureau of Water.
Subjects:
Engineering.; Presidents--United States--Election--1912.; Railroads.; Railroads--Design and construction.; Engineers.
Places:
Colombia--Description and travel.; Colombia--Surveys.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1843-1893 (Box 1)
- Correspondence (Box 1)
- Legal documents, receipts, 1843-1849 (Box 1)
  Ritter estate
- Accounts, 1872-1883 (Box 1)
- Will, 1875 (Box 1)
  William Trautwine, Sr.
- Records, 1883 (Box 1)
  John C. Trautwine Estate et al.
- Records, 1660-1906 (Box 1)
  Bradford Family
- Genealogy, n.d. (Box 1)
  Trautwine Genealogy
- Miscellany, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1896-1942 (Box 2)
- Correspondence (Box 2)
- Personal Files (Box 2)
  (alphabetically arranged) A-B: correspondence, biographical material, news clippings, includes Samuel H. Ashbridge; A.S.E. Ackermann; Walter Atlee
- Personal Files (Box 3)
  B-H: includes Charles R. and Edwin H. Barker; Jules Beloin; Clinton L. Bogart; Charton P. Bolles; Lydia T. Boring; Maynard Boice; Mrs. C. Robert Grimm
- Personal Files (Box 4)
  H-T: includes Rudolph Hering; Helen V. Hughes; Max Livingston; Morris, Wheeler and Co.; Capt. John Montresor; Myretetus (genealogy); George W. Penfield
- Personal Files, 1908-1944 (Box 4)
  William H. Balch
- Personal Files, 1945-1948 (Box 5)
- Personal Files, n.d. (Box 5)
  C
- Subject Files (Box 6)
  (alphabetically arranged): includes arch bridges; bridges; pumps; engines; politics; pollution; railroads; religion
- Subject Files (Box 7)
  Religion; Rochester and Lake Ontario Water Co.; Sanitation; War; Water; also J.C. Trautwine III, personal
- Volumes, 1866-1891 (Box 8)
  Diaries, accounts (very fragile)
- Volumes (Box 9)
  Photo albums, poetry book, sketch book, notes
- Photographs (Box 10)
- Miscellany, 1902-1923 (Box 11)
  Theatre programs, miscellany
- Correspondence, 1903-1915 (Box 12)
  Correspondence 1903-1915; J.C. Trautwine III, 1909-1911
- Miscellany, n.d. (Box 12)
  Bradford Family 1660-1906
- Photographs, n.d. (Box 13)
- Maps (Box 13)
  Anthracite Coal Regions of Pennsylvania; Canton Berne